A Guide to the Boxwood Garden Club Records, 1937-2007, 2012, 2017
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Boxwood Garden Club Records, 1937-2007, 2012, 2017
The Library of Virginia
43899, 52360
7.2 cu. ft. and 12 boxes
Boxwood Garden Club
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Boxwood Garden Club, Richmond, Virginia
Historical Information
The Boxwood Garden Club was founded in 1937 in Richmond, Virginia. The club is a member club in the Garden Club of Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1937-2007, 2012, 2017, of the Boxwood Garden Club of Richmond, Virginia, containing meeting minutes, attendance records, yearbooks, financial reports, bank records, by-laws, programs, registers, photographs, slides, clippings, articles, magazines, and other materials concerning the Boxwood Garden Club's activities, programs, community service, and projects, as well as its role as a member of the Garden Club of Virginia. Collection is organized into the following series: Series I: Minutes, 1945-2205. Series II: Organization Reports and Records, 1937-2003. Series III: Yearbooks, 1979-2007. Series IV: Tablescapes and Tablescapes II, 1985-1987. Series V: Garden Club of Virginia, 1979-2002. Series VI: Miscellaneous. Series VII: Scrapbooks, 1937-2005.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Minutes, 1945-2005.
Series II: Organization Reports and Records, 1937-2003, 2012.
Series III: Yearbooks, 1979-2007.
Series IV: Tablescapes and Tablescapes II, 1985-1987.
Series V: Garden Club of Virginia, 1979-2002.
Series VI: Miscellaneous.
Series VII: Scrapbooks, 1937-2007.
Contents List
- Series I: Minutes, 1945-2005., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 1-2)
  Minutes, 1945-2005 contains minutes for monthly meetings, executive meetings, and annual meetings; agendas; attendance; financial reports; reports; yearbooks; and other materials detailing the activities of the Boxwood Garden Club.
  - Minutes, 1945-1949 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance, yearbooks). (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1949-1950 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance, yearbooks). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1950-1953 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance, yearbooks). (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1953-1958 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance). (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1957-1965 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1965-1967 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance, financial reports, agendas). (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1968-1969 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance, Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting minutes). (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1969-1971 (includes executive meeting minutes, attendance). (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1971-1975 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance). (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1977-1979 (includes annual reports, agendas, executive meeting minutes and other papers). (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1979-1982 (includes annual and executive meeting minutes, attendance, financial reports, and other papers). (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1982-1983 (includes attendance, financial papers). (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1983-1985 (includes annual meeting minutes, attendance, financial reports, reports, and other papers). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1985-1988 (includes financial statements, attendance, constitutional changes, application). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1986, 1989-1992 (includes annual meeting minutes, attendance). (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1993-2001 (includes annual meeting minutes, histories, and other papers). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1995-1997 (includes agendas, reports, financial papers, and other papers). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1999-2001 (includes fliers, by-laws changes). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and papers, 2001-2003 (folder 1 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and papers, 2001-2003 (folder 2 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes and papers, 2001-2003 (folder 3 of 3). (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes and papers, 2003-2005. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series II: Organization Reports and Records, 1937-2003, 2012., Extent: 1 box. (Box 3)
  Organization Reports and Records, 1937-2003, contains annual reports, bank book, bank records, by-laws, financial reports, treasurer's reports, histories, State Corporation Commission papers, and Internal Revenue Service papers for the Boxwood Garden Club.
  - Annual reports, 1951-1957. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual reports, 1958-1965. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Annual reports, 1965-1969. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Annual reports, 1969-1975. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annual reports, 1969-1986. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Organization papers, 1984-1985 (SCC and IRS papers, by-laws, bank papers). (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Record of motions passed, 1937-1967. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letters written, 1963-1975. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Histories, 1937-1982. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Historian's papers, 1991-2003. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - DVD--Celebrating 75 Years-Boxwood Garden Club,2012. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Treasurer's reports and bank book, 1937-1965 (bank book, 1955-1961). (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1965-1972. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series III: Yearbooks, 1979-2007., Extent: 1 box. (Box 4)
  Yearbooks, 1979-2007, consisting of the yearbooks of the Boxwood Garden Club contains membership information.
  - Yearbooks, 1979-1982. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Yearbooks, 1982-1986. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Yearbooks, 1987-1991. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Yearbooks, 1991-1994. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Yearbooks, 1994-1996. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Yearbooks, 1996-1998, 2006-2007. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Tablescapes and Tablescapes II, 1985-1987., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 4-5)
  Tablescapes, 1985, and Tablescapes II, 1987, contains advertising, brochures, fliers, programs, reports, negatives, photographs, slides, and other papers relating to the Boxwood Garden Club programs Tablescapes and Tablescapes II.
  - Tablescapes, 1985, planning. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Tablescapes, 1985, photographs and negatives. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tablescapes, 1985, slides. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Tablescapes, 1985, miscellaneous papers. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, publicity. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, publicity report, including advertising. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, brochures and pamphlets (see also box 9, folders 3-4). (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, planning. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, miscellaneous papers. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, miscellaneous papers and photographs. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, slides. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Series V: Garden Club of Virginia, 1979-2002., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 5-7)
  Garden Club of Virginia, 1979-2002, contains programs for annual meetings and Board of Governors meetings; member register and supplement to register, 2000-2002; materials for the Garden Club of Virginia meeting in Richmond in 1979; and programs, photographs, thank-you notes, and other materials for the Garden Club of Virginia meeting in Richmond in 1999.
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting, 1979, programs, registers, Garden Club of Virginia Journal. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting, 1979, invitations, reservation cards, correspondence, miscellaneous. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting, 1979, maps and mementos. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting, 1999, miscellaneous materials. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting photographs, 1999, reception, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting photographs, 1999, reception, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts; reception, Maymont. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting photographs, 1999, reception, Maymont. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting photographs, 1999, meeting, Jefferson Hotel. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting photographs, 1999, reception, Jefferson Hotel. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting thank-you notes and cards, 13-14 May 1999. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting thank-you notes and cards, 15-16 May 1999. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting thank-you notes and cards, 17 May 1999. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting thank-you notes and cards, 18 May 1999. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting thank-you notes and cards, 19 May-June 1999. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Garden Club of Virginia [annual meeting?], [1999?], photographs and negatives. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting, 2001. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual meeting, 2002. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Garden Club of Virginia Board of Governors, 1987. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Garden Club of Virginia Board of Governors, 2001. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Garden Club of Virginia Board of Governors, 2001-2002. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Garden Club of Virginia register and supplement to register, 2000-2002. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Miscellaneous., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 7-9)
  Miscellaneous contains articles, art work, awards, certificates, clippings, correspondence, magazines, medals, meeting minutes, notes, photographs, postors, rosters, slides, and other materials concerning Bandy Field (Richmond, Va.), the Three Chopt Garden Club, the Tuckahoe Garden Club, the James River Garden Club, the Hampton Roads Garden Club, the Garden Club of the Middle Peninsula, flowers, Garden Club of Virginia rose shows, Gunston Hall gardens, and Garden Gossip magazine
  - Boxwood Garden Club 70th Anniversary, 2007. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1999, no date. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Historic Garden Week, 2002, slides. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bettie Pardee talk, 1993, papers and slides. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sybil Sylvester book discussion, 2017. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Mary Glen Taylor papers. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Bandy Field papers, 2003. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bandy Field photographs, 2003. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Meeting of the four Garden Club of Virginia clubs, 1987-1988. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hampton Roads Garden Club yearbook, 2005-2006. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Garden Club of the Middle Peninsula yearbook, 2005-2006. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - James River Garden Club yearbook, 2005-2006. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Tuckahoe Garden Club of Westhampton yearbook, 2005-2006. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Water Damage to Boxwoods. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - What Are Those Arrangers Up To Now? (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Christmas Decorations in Elizabethan Times. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Let's Grow Lilies handbook. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - A Source List of Garden Flowers. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Garden Club of Virginia 35th Annual Rose Show, 1971. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - The Restoration of the Garden at Gunston Hall. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Garden Gossip magazine, 1931, 1941, 1943, 1954, 1955. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Clippings. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Garden Club of Virginia Yearly Award for Outstanding Work (Massie Medal), no date, to the Boxwood Garden Club. (Box 8)
  - Garden Club of Virginia Yearly Award for Outstanding Work (Massie Medal), 1953, to the Boxwood Garden Club. (Box 8)
  - Garden Club of Virginia de Lacy Gray Medal, 1970, to the Boxwood Garden Club. (Box 8)
  - Certificate of Recognition from the City of Richmond to the Boxwood Garden Club, 2002. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit slip form. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, art work (see also box 5, folder 3). (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Tablescapes II, 1987, poster (see also box 5, folder 3). (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Garden Club of Virginia 53rd Annual Rose Show art, 1989. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Note card artwork. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Series VII: Scrapbooks, 1937-2005., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 9-11)
  Scrapbooks, 1937-2005, contains advertisements, awards, brochures, clippings, correspondence, fliers, guides, invitations, magazines, minutes, name tags, photographs, plans, programs, reports, telegrams, yearbooks, clippings, correspondence, awards, telegrams, yearbooks, and other materials chronicling the history of the Boxwood Garden Club.
  - Scrapbook, 1993-1999. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 2003-2005. (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1955-1961. (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1966. (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1966-1976. (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1976-1993. (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1937-1955. (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook for Tablescapes II, 1987. (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook for Tablescapes II, 1987. (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook for Garden Club of Virginia meeting, 1999. (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1999-2000. (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook, 2001-2003. (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook, 2002-2003. (Box 11)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual lily show scrapbook (Boxwood Garden Club), 1997-2007. (Box 12)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual rose show scrapbook (Boxwood Garden Club), 2000-2004. (Box 12)
  - Garden Club of Virginia annual daffodil show scrapbook (Boxwood Garden Club), 2000-2007. (Box 12)